<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ahoy There! on Sanjay PJ</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Ahoy There! on Sanjay PJ</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>{year}</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:29:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanjaypj.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Declarative UI is Reshaping the Developer's Workflow</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/declarative-vs-imperative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/declarative-vs-imperative/</guid><description>The other day, nostalgia hit me hard. I found myself diving back into Android development after what felt like ages.</description></item><item><title>The Evolution of Motorcycle Manufacturing: From Classic Charm to Modern Precision</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/classic-to-modern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:20:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/classic-to-modern/</guid><description>Motorcycles have always been more than just a way to get from one place to another.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Virtual DOM: A Simple Implementation Guide</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/understanding-virtual-dom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 19:58:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/understanding-virtual-dom/</guid><description>In modern web development, efficient rendering is crucial for creating responsive applications. One of the most popular approaches to improving performance is the Virtual DOM.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Background and Foreground Services in Android: A Friendly Guide</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/background-foreground-services-android-guide/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 09:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/background-foreground-services-android-guide/</guid><description>Hey there, fellow tech enthusiasts! If you’ve ever dived into the world of Android app development, you might have stumbled upon terms like background services and foreground services.</description></item><item><title>Can Socialism and Capitalism Coexist? The Sweet Spot.</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/rethinking-socialism-and-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/rethinking-socialism-and-capitalism/</guid><description>Lately, I’ve been thinking a lot about The Motorcycle Diaries—you know, the one about the young Ernesto &amp;ldquo;Che&amp;rdquo; Guevara traveling across South America and slowly realizing how messed up things are for the poor.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Rome in Assassin’s Creed: Brotherhood: Where History Meets Gameplay</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/rome-a-city-that-breathes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:19:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/rome-a-city-that-breathes/</guid><description>As a kid, I was captivated by stories of kings and conquests, enchanted by tales of brave heroes who traversed vast empires, battled fierce enemies, and transformed the world around them.</description></item><item><title>Why You Should Choose an Incorporated Consulting Team</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/why-incorporated-consulting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/why-incorporated-consulting/</guid><description>When it comes to finding the right consulting partner, it’s worth considering whether they’re incorporated. You might be wondering, “What’s the big deal?</description></item><item><title>Exploring the Main Gameplay Mechanics of The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/zelda-the-minish-cap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 09:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/zelda-the-minish-cap/</guid><description>A Link to The Past I still remember playing Mario, Tetris, and Pac-Man for hours as a kid on some knock-off NES console my parents got me.</description></item><item><title>Horizontal Pod Autoscaling with Kubernetes</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/horizontal-pod-autoscaling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 09:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/horizontal-pod-autoscaling/</guid><description>Kubernetes, the powerful orchestration platform for containerized applications, offers numerous features to ensure that your applications are running efficiently and scaling as needed.</description></item><item><title>Hugo: A Simple Approach to Blogging</title><link>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/why-chose-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 09:16:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanjaypj.github.io/posts/why-chose-hugo/</guid><description>So, I’ve decided to use Hugo for my blog, and honestly, I think I got a bit inspired by Nithin Kamath’s site.</description></item></channel></rss>